Rhitam Dutta

rhitamdutta1996@gmail.com | +91 7019679084 | Github | LinkedIn | Itch.io

SUMMARY

AWS Certified Developer Associate and Software Engineer with over two years of experience in Cloud Computing, Web Development, and Health Information Technology. Seeking to leverage strong leadership and software development skills to increase profitability for The Goldman Sachs Group, Inc.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

August 2020 - now

Cerner Corporation — Cardiology Department

- Helped transfer critical patient data across various departments in Cerner by implementing Java service calls and API(s).
- Responsible for adding new functionality for Cerner proprietary EMR solution "Powerchart" that enabled doctors to declare a study attached to a medical procedure as matched in error. Before the inerror functionality, procedures had to be cancelled and initiated again. Technologies used included Visual C++, Java, and Oracle.
- Updated and deployed proprietary Maven dependencies used across Cerner to decrease vulnerability and increase security.
- Automated testing using Eggplant for various workflows.

Software Intern

January 2020 - July 2020

 $Cerner\ Corporation\ --\ Radiology\ Department$

 Developed a mini multilingual hospital portal system using Spring MVC and Hibernate. Parts of it were integrated into the EHR known as Cerner Millennium.

Web Analyst Intern

May 2019 - June 2019

National Informatics Centre

 Enabled enhanced server logging of various government websites for web traffic analysis by developing custom scripts using PHP and MySQL.

PROJECTS

Rhitam Dutta Online Coaching (Django, Vanilla JavaScript, Amazon Web Services) August 2020

— As the pandemic worsened in India and gyms shut down, I built an online coaching platform on top of my portfolio website that allowed me to help people from all around the world be strong, physically fit, and healthy through my experience as a strength coach. A receipt gets sent after a successful purchase and my team contacts the client for further communication.

Angel Bot (Discord.js, Discord-Akairo, TypeScript)

May 2020

Angel is a self-made, open-source, all-encompassing Discord bot that does everything from managing users to
entertaining them with sardonic quips. Equipped with numerous functionalities, it continues to be used by an
ever-increasing number of server administrators and moderators everyday.

Weather Data Analyzer and Forecaster (Hadoop and Map Reduce)

January 2017 - April 2017

— As there is an ever-increasing need for designing system architecture that helps to predict weather forecast, I built a weather analyser and forecaster. It takes in weather data from NCDC (National Climatic Data Center) and loads it into Apache Pig. Hive processes the data and performs parallel key operations to categorize the weather based on hot or cold days. Then, on each data chunk it performed K nearest neighbor to predict the future weather data.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, C/C++, TypeScript (ES6), C#, SQL, Unix

Frameworks: Django, Spring, Hibernate, Docker, TensorFlow, Flutter, Hadoop, Bootstrap, .NET, Node, React

Tools: Amazon AWS, Unity Game Engine, Photoshop, Illustrator, Heroku, DigitalOcean, Bash, Git, LATEX

EDUCATION